RAFAEL LEÓN TORRES Software Developer - .NET

in linkedin.com/in/rafael-leon-torres-75410999



Over the past six years, I have honed my backend development skills, focusing on the design and implementation of Windows services and adding new functionalities to Windows desktop applications using the .NET Framework. More recently, I have worked with newer frameworks like .NET 6, utilizing Service Workers. Additionally, I have designed and implemented Web APIs in .NET 6, leveraging the Entity Framework to manage SQL Server databases while applying SQLID principles to these components.

On the database side, I have designed and optimized stored procedures for handling large volumes of information, analyzed dependencies across multiple databases, and used JSON to simplify inserts, queries, and updates.

While working at CECOBAN, I gained experience in improving the performance of various batch components, APIs and websites for the billing process. In this role, I served as a technical lead, responsible for the analysis, design, and implementation of complete processes for different clients. I applied SOLID principles and design patterns to achieve better implementations, ensuring that over time, maintenance would be easier.

While working for NTT DATA, I was involved in migrating all components to new infrastructure. This required extensive analysis and modifications to software components, including desktop applications, APIs, and databases. My responsibilities included making the necessary changes to achieve this migration, such as enrolling database accounts (creating them, granting permissions, and testing them). For the software side, I configured deployments to different environments, tested them, and resolved any issues that arose. This process applied to both production and non-production environments.

To accomplish all this, I had to raise tickets that were addressed by personnel in other countries, seeking support for issues I could not resolve myself.

In my free time, I continuously learn new technologies and deepen my knowledge of C# and .NET to further advance my professional career.



EDUCATION

UG, 2012 - 2016 BSc. Electronics and Communications Engineering

Towa Software, 2018 Engineering Warrior, Java & C#



PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

NTT DATA 2022 - 2024

Solutions Team Leader, NTT DATA EUROPE & LATAM, CDMX

- > Migrate the applications and APIs to new infrastructure and testing.
- > Implement new functionalities for Windows desktop Banks applications
- > Add new functionalities to the APIs(NET 6) we used
- > Enhance Performance of different BD components
- > Continuous integration and continuous deployment Bit Bucket, Jenkins
- > Unit Testing
- > Analysis and Design of SQL Server Structure, Scripts and Stored Procedures
- > Agile & SCRUM Methodologies (Planning, Design, Stand ups, Release Iterations)
- > Working and supporting QA Team
- > Working in a multicultural Team to solve different issues

C# GIT BitBucket CI/CD SQL Server Sonar Cloud Windows Forms WPF

CECOBAN 2019 - 2022

C# .NET Developer, CECOBAN, CDMX

- > Analysis of Client Requirements
- > Architecture Design
- > Design of Components (Worker services, APIs)
- > Enhance Performance of different components
- > Continuous integration and continuous deployment Azure DevOps
- > Analysis and Design of SQL Server Structure, Scripts and Stored Procedures
- > Resolve Vulnerabilities (Sonar Cloud)
- > Agile & SCRUM Methodologies (Planning, Design, Stand ups, Release Iterations)
- > Working and supporting QA Team
- > Design and enhance of Stored procedures in SQL Server
- > Monitoring in real time using Grafana

C# | Microsoft Azure | TFVC | CI/CD | SQL Server | Sonar Cloud | Entity Framework

Towa Software 2018 - 2019

Jr. Software Developer, CECOBAN, CDMX

- > .NET Core Trainning
- > Clean code Trainning
- > Rampup Process with CECOBAN

Java C# SQL Server

+ HARDSKILLS

- > OOP C++, C#
- > SOLID Principles
- > Windows services, Worker services (NET 5 Y 6)
- > Windows Forms, WPF
- > Web API's
- > JSON
- > XML
- > Micro services
- > CI/CD Azure Devops, Jenkins
- > SQL Server
- > Version Control Management TFVC, BITBUCKET
- > Entity Framework
- > WCF
- > MVC
- > Javascript
- > Grafana
- > Job Scheduler with Quartz
- > LINQ

+ SOFTSKILLS

- > Verbal and Written Communication
- > Time Management
- > Empathy
- > Teamwork
- > Ownership
- > Creativity
- > Responsibility
- > Collaboration
- > Adaptability
- > Organization

66 REFERENCES

Mauricio Ramos

Software engineer, Kueski

@ Mauricio.ramos@kueski.com

+52 55 79 60 15 60

Marcelo Fernandez

Sofware Developer Sr. Net, CECOBAN

@ mfernandez@cecoban.org.mx

+52 55 21 04 77 17

Jesús Santiago Sánchez

Sofware Developer Sr. Net, QUALIS TECHNOLOGIES

@ jesus.santiagosanchez11@gmail.com

+52 77 12 834011